<JOBS>
<JOB>
<JOBTITLE>
<![CDATA[ C.N.A./Mental Health Technician - Caring Hands Senior Services ]]>
</JOBTITLE>
<JOBLOCATION>
<![CDATA[ Memorial Hospital and HCC-MHC ]]>
</JOBLOCATION>
<JOBBODY>
<![CDATA[ <p><strong>Job Summary </strong></p> <p>The Mental Health Technician assists professional nursing staff by performing supportive and complementary tasks in patient care activities under direct supervision and in conjunction with the other team members. Performs routine department duties. Interacts with patients in a supportive and professional manner. Demonstrates knowledge of developmental needs of patient population specific to the Behavioral Health Services Department. (Patient population is defined in each department's Scope of Practice.)</p> <p>&nbsp;<strong>Qualifications </strong></p> <p><u>Education: <br /></u>High school diploma or equivalent required. Associate Degree in Psychology or related field preferred. <br /><br /><u>Training: <br /></u>Four to six weeks orientation with preceptor. CPR Provider-C required within 30 days of hire. CPI certification within one year. Certified Nursing Assistant required or plan to obtain Certified Nursing Assistant designation within one year of hire required.</p> <p><u>Experience: <br /></u>Previous experience in a health care facility or psychiatric setting preferred. <br /><br /><u>Job Knowledge, Skills, and Abilities: <br /></u>Establishes therapeutic interactions with patients and performs selected patient care activities under the direction and supervision of a registered nurse. Records and reports pertinent information to the registered nurse and assists with department support duties as directed. Successful completion of skills checklist within sixty days.</p> <p><strong>Performance Requirements </strong></p> <div><u>Responsibility for: <br /></u>Providing maximum patient care within limits defined by delegated tasks. Maintaining patient safety and comfort, infection control, and Standard Precautions. Maintaining a safe and clean nursing department. Utilizing supplies efficiently. <br /><br /><u>Physical Demands: <br /></u>On feet for major portion of the day. Much pulling, pushing, and lifting may be required. Good communication skills required. Visual, auditory, and speech acuity essential to giving patient care and evaluating patient needs. Works in nursing department and patient rooms which are well lighted, heated, and ventilated; some exposure to disagreeable conditions. May come in contact with hazardous health conditions; however, if proper procedure is followed no harm should come to employee. <br /><br /><u>Special Demands: <br /></u>Reflects the mission, philosophy, core values, and customer service plan of Memorial Hospital and Health Care Center in action and attitude. Ability to work under close supervision and to follow verbal and written instructions under sometimes stressful conditions. Must be able to work with all disciplines and use tact and good judgment in dealing with varying conditions. Maintains confidentiality. May be required to work rotating shifts and a reasonable amount of overtime. <br /><br /></div><br><br><div>Day shift&nbsp;- 6am to 3:30pm - may vary</div> <div>Every 3rd Weekend</div><br><br>Equal Opportunity Employer Minorities/Women/Protected Veterans/Disabled ]]>
</JOBBODY>
<JOBLINK>
<![CDATA[ https://recruiting.adp.com/srccsh/public/RTI.home?r=5000663423306&c=1127707&d=ExternalCareerSite&rb=LINKEDIN ]]>
</JOBLINK>
<REQNUMBER>
<![CDATA[ 5000663423306 ]]>
</REQNUMBER>
<CATEGORY>
<![CDATA[ ]]>
</CATEGORY>
<FULLTIME>
<![CDATA[ Part-time ]]>
</FULLTIME>
<LOCATIONCITY>
<![CDATA[ Jasper ]]>
</LOCATIONCITY>
<LOCATIONSTATE>
<![CDATA[ IN ]]>
</LOCATIONSTATE>
<LOCATIONZIP>
<![CDATA[ 47546 ]]>
</LOCATIONZIP>
<LOCATIONCOUNTRY>
<![CDATA[ USA ]]>
</LOCATIONCOUNTRY>
<OPENDATE>
<![CDATA[ 11/11/2020 ]]>
</OPENDATE>
<EXPIREDATE>
<![CDATA[ ]]>
</EXPIREDATE>
<COMPANY>
<![CDATA[ Memorial Hospital and Health Care ]]>
</COMPANY>
</JOB>
<JOB>
<JOBTITLE>
<![CDATA[ Case Manager - Utilization Review ]]>
</JOBTITLE>
<JOBLOCATION>
<![CDATA[ Memorial Hospital and HCC-MHC ]]>
</JOBLOCATION>
<JOBBODY>
<![CDATA[ <div><strong>Job Summary</strong> <br />Case Managers are financial managers, problem solvers, facilitators, counselors, planning consultants, educators, and advocates. The RN Case Manager promotes a collaborative process that requires assessing, developing, implementing, coordinating, monitoring, and evaluating the services required to meet an individual's health needs. She/He is responsible and accountable for coordinating the care of clients across a continuum of care, facilitating the achievement of quality, clinical and cost outcomes, and coordinating services and resources needed by the client. Demonstrates knowledge of developmental needs of patient population specific to that department. (Patient population is defined in each department's Scope of Practice.) <br /><br /><strong>Qualifications</strong> <br />Education:&nbsp;</div> <div>BSN or other Bachelor's in other health-related field required. Graduate from an accredited school of nursing preferred with current registration in Indiana required. CPR Provider C required within 30 days of hire.&nbsp;<br /><br />Training: <br />Require four to six weeks orientation with close supervision for six months to one year.</div> <div style="font-size: 4.0px;">&nbsp;</div> <div>Experience: <br />Three to five years experience in acute care/critical care nursing. Independent critical thinking skills.</div> <div style="font-size: 4.0px;">&nbsp;</div> <div>Job Knowledge, Skills and Abilities: <br />Excellent communication and organizational skills. Thorough knowledge of Hospital inpatient, observation, and discharge criteria. Familiar with organizational, policies, and procedures of hospital as they relate to Patient Services. Must have the ability to function as an individual as well as be an active member of the interdisciplinary team. Completion of basic skills checklist within 60 days. Verification of competency in basic job knowledge, skills, and ability as specified per individual department. Provides education for the patient addressing the educational needs that have been identified. <br /><br /><strong>Performance Requirements</strong> <br />Responsibility for: <br />Coordinates with the multidisciplinary team to facilitate progress with the plan of care. Collaborates with the attending physician regarding patient progress and outcomes. Facilitates interdisciplinary rounds for assigned patients. Anticipates and identifies variances related to patients individual needs. Coordinates with Social Work timely and comprehensive discharge planning. Reviews and manages appropriate resource consumption. Facilitates effective communication between the health care team, patients and family members. Follows through to assure patient issues are appropriately resolved in a timely manner. Collaborates with third party payers to insure that admission criteria is met, and to certify acute care and/or post-hospital services. Guides physicians and staff with regard to admission status (inpatient, outpatient, observation) and process. Assists in the collection of data from patient charts as needed.</div> <div style="font-size: 4.0px;">&nbsp;</div> <div>Physical Demands: <br />Walks, sits and stands intermittently. Must have auditory, visual and verbal skills to review written documents and communicate with nursing staff, Medical Staff and insurance companies via telephone. Works in office areas and departments which are well-lighted, heated and ventilated. May come in contact with hazardous health conditions; however, if proper procedure is followed no harm should come to employee.</div> <div style="font-size: 4.0px;">&nbsp;</div> <div>Special Demands: <br />Willingness to work with realization that errors may have serious consequences for patients, physicians and facility. Nurses are encouraged to be actively involved in the community as leaders in health and wellness promotion and injury and disease prevention. Competency, tact, and patience are necessary when communicating with patients, families, physicians, and other personnel. Develop and implement techniques and/or procedures to meet the needs of physicians, patients and other personnel. Reflects the mission, philosophy, core values, and customer service plan of Memorial Hospital and Health Care Center in action and attitude. Nursing practice reflects the American Nurses Association Code of Ethics.</div><br><br><div><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">BSN or other Bachelor's in other health-related field required. </span></div> <div><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Require four to six weeks orientation with close supervision for six months to one year.</span></div> <div><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;"><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Three to five years experience in acute care/critical care nursing required and independent critical thinking skills. <br /></span></span> <p><u><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Utilization Review</span></u></p> <ul style="margin-top: 0.0in;"> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Performs timely clinical reviews to ensure medical necessity (initial, continued stay and retro)</span></li> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Reviews and manages appropriate resource consumption</span></li> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Collaborates with third party payers to ensure that admission criteria is met, and to certify acute care and/or post-hospital services</span></li> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Guides physicians and healthcare team with regard to admission status (inpatient, outpatient, observation) and process</span></li> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Assists in the collection of data from patient charts as needed</span></li> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Anticipate/identifies patient variance days to reduce avoidable days</span></li> <li><span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;">Performs Observation chart audits</span></li> </ul> <span style="font-family: Tahoma , sans-serif;font-size: 11.0pt;"><br /><br /></span></div><br><br>Equal Opportunity Employer Minorities/Women/Protected Veterans/Disabled ]]>
</JOBBODY>
<JOBLINK>
<![CDATA[ https://recruiting.adp.com/srccsh/public/RTI.home?r=5000639748806&c=1127707&d=ExternalCareerSite&rb=LINKEDIN ]]>
</JOBLINK>
<REQNUMBER>
<![CDATA[ 5000639748806 ]]>
</REQNUMBER>
<CATEGORY>
<![CDATA[ ]]>
</CATEGORY>
<FULLTIME>
<![CDATA[ Part-time ]]>
</FULLTIME>
<LOCATIONCITY>
<![CDATA[ Jasper ]]>
</LOCATIONCITY>
<LOCATIONSTATE>
<![CDATA[ IN ]]>
</LOCATIONSTATE>
<LOCATIONZIP>
<![CDATA[ 47546 ]]>
</LOCATIONZIP>
<LOCATIONCOUNTRY>
<![CDATA[ USA ]]>
</LOCATIONCOUNTRY>
<OPENDATE>
<![CDATA[ 9/1/2020 ]]>
</OPENDATE>
<EXPIREDATE>
<![CDATA[ ]]>
</EXPIREDATE>
<COMPANY>
<![CDATA[ Memorial Hospital and Health Care ]]>
</COMPANY>
</JOB>
</JOBS>